Inventory of the Miller Upton papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Miller Upton papers
1927-1990
90007
Hoover Institution Archives
25 manuscript boxes (10.2 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, conference material, reports, printed matter, and miscellany relating to American participation in international cooperative activities, especially in the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization; international education; the Federal Union; and economics.
Upton, Miller, 1916-2005.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1916 Born, New Orleans
1940- Taught economics at Lake Forest College
1944- Taught finance at Northwestern University
1950 Associate professor, Washington University in St. Louis
1951- Dean, School of Business and Public Administration, Washington University in St. Louis
1953 Co-author, Introduction to Business Finance
1954-1975 President, Beliot College
1961-1966 Chairman and public interest director, Federal Home Loan Bank Board of Chicago
1970-1974 United States delegate to the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO)
1971-1974 Chairman, United States National Commission for UNESCO
2005 Died
Source: Yue, Lorene. "Robinson Miller Upton." Chicago Tribune 22 December 2005. Accessed through: http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2005-12-22/news/0512220101_1_mr-upton-independent-colleges-and-universities-student
Scope and Content of Collection
The Miller Upton papers include writings, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, conference material, reports, printed matter, and miscellany related to American participation in international cooperative activities, especially in the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO); international education; the Federal Union; and economics. Although the collection has not been arranged, the index to major groups can serve as a guide to the materials.
Throughout his career, Miller Upton held a variety of roles related to the field of education, including professor, college president, and delegate to UNESCO. He was interested in working with international organizations to achieve education goals. The collection includes Correspondence dating from 1962 to 1975, during which time he served as president of Beloit College and a delegate to UNESCO. His Speeches and Writings contain articles related to economics, as well as commencement addresses.
From 1960 to 1961, Upton served as chairman of Governor Gaylord A. Nelson's "Blue Ribbon Tax Committee," which revamped Wisconsin's tax structure. The Continuing Revenue Survey Commission File includes commission reports, meeting minutes, and correspondence related to this project.
In May 1970, Upton wrote an open letter to President Nixon regarding the Kent State shootings. Although Upton opposed the Vietnam War, a point that he affirmed in the letter, he apologized for the "grotesque failure of the academic community at this hour of national trial and turmoil," and wrote, "If the fault lies anywhere for the Kent State deaths it lies not with you and the Vietnam War but with the radical acts and excesses we have tolerated in the name of dissent." The letter was originally published in a student newspaper, but went on to receive national attention. The Richard M. Nixon File includes Upton's open letter, clippings, and responses.
From 1970 to 1974, Upton was a United States delegate to UNESCO. During that time, he also served as the chairman to the United States National Commission for UNESCO, a group that functioned as a Federal Advisory Committee to the Department of State. In 1974, Upton was the chairman of the United States delegation to the 18th General Conference. The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) File includes correspondence, conference materials, reports, and speeches documenting Upton's involvement with UNESCO.
From 1975 to 1976, Upton served as a consultant to a special committee of the Association of American Colleges to determine the future role of the Association. The Association of American Colleges File includes meeting materials, correspondence, memoranda, and notes documenting Upton's work for the organization.
From 1976 to 1980, Upton served as CEO and chairman of the Federal Union, a British organization, formed in 1939 and incorporated in 1940, advocating a federal union of Europe as a post-war aim to defend against totalitarianism. The organization was committed to furthering ideas proposed in the book Union Now by Clarence K. Streit. The Federal Union File includes correspondence, memoranda, printed matter (including issues of Freedom & Union), meeting minutes, and clippings.
In a note concerning his philosophy of life, Upton wrote, "Should someone ever want to give me a tag, let it be 'a conservative for liberal reasons'" (Box 7, Folder 11). Upton was a pacifist and conscientious objector during WWII, and wrote, "I am and have been throughout my adult life passionately opposed to war. It is the ultimate human folly. It is man's power of reason perverted to the extreme. It is the antithesis of the essence of Christ's teachings." ("Federal Union—A Practical Means to Peace," Box 12, Folder 6).
Index to Major Groups
Although the collection is not physically arranged, most materials fall into the following groups.
1-2 Personal File, 1954-1975:
Includes correspondence, clippings, and photographs related to business and personal matters. Includes photographs of Miller Upton.
2 Correspondence, 1962-1975:
Includes incoming and outgoing letters from 1962 to 1975, arranged chronologically.
2, 3-7, 9-10, 24 Speeches and Writings, 1946-1990:
Includes typescripts and printed copies of speeches and writings related to economics, business, and finance, as well as commencement addresses. Includes related correspondence and notes.
23-24 Continuing Revenue Survey Commission File, 1959-1961:
Includes correspondence, memoranda, reports, meeting minutes, notes, and charts related to the tax system of Wisconsin.
8-9 Richard M. Nixon File, 1970-1976:
Includes materials related to an open letter to Nixon regarding the Kent State shootings, as well as letters received in response.
16-22 United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) File, 1960-1987:
Includes correspondence, conference materials, reports, and speeches related to the UNESCO General Conference (Sessions 16 through 18) and the United States National Commission.
22 Association of American Colleges File, 1974-1976:
Includes correspondence, reports, and meeting materials. Contains documentation related to Upton's work as a consultant to determine the future role of the organization.
11-16, 24 Federal Union File, 1927-1986:
Includes correspondence, memoranda, printed matter (including issues of Freedom & Union), meeting minutes, and clippings. Arranged alphabetically.
International cooperation.; Unesco.; U.S. National Commission for UNESCO.; International education.; Education.; International organization.; Federal Union.; Economics.; United States--Foreign relations.
- Personal File
  - 1954-1961 (Box-folder 1: 1-3)
  - 1962-1964 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - 1975 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Correspondence
  - 1962-1970 (Box-folder 2: 2-3)
  - 1971-1974 (Box-folder 2: 4-5)
  - 1975 (Box-folder 2: 6-7)
- Speeches and Writings
  - "Leadership, Motivation, and the Liberal Arts,", undated (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - 1954 June. "Education for the Profession of Leadership," Beloit commencement address (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - 1954 September. "Integration--The Watchword of Formal Education," (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - 1955 June. "So What," commencement address, Harlem High School (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - 1955 June. "Where Do You Go From Here?," commencement address, Beloit Memorial High School, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - 1955 July. "Commencement Address, Northwestern University Summer Session," (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - 1955 July. "The Essential Kinship of Religion and Higher Education," (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - 1956 March. "Current Trends in Higher Education and Their Implications for Beloit College," Annual Alumni Conference, Baloit College (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - 1956 May. "Truth Is Where You Find It," Honors Day convocation address, Crinnell College (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - 1956 December. "The Rising Tide,", 1956-1957 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - 1957 February. "Progressive Reaction," Founders' Day Address, Wayland Academy, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - 1957 March. "Educational Gyroscopes,", 1958 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - 1958 September. "Opening Convocation Address," (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - 1959 February. "The Real Mission of the Church,", 1959-1960 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - 1959 September. "The Majesty of Self," opening vespers, 1939, 1959 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - 1960 April. Convocation statement (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - 1960 October. "The Priest and the Prophet," (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - 1960 November. "My Living Philosophy," Chicago Sunday Evening Club (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - 1961 March. "Educational needs in the Sixties and Their Economic Implications," (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - 1962 September. "The College Library--Mausoleum or Valhalla?" opening vespers (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - 1962 September. "Society's Need for Authenticity," CLU Annual Meeting (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - 1963 February. "Society's Need for Authenticity," convocation address (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - 1963 March. "Higher Education Today," (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - 1963 May. "A Delcaration of Independence," Clinton High School (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - 1963 September. "Sounding Brass or a Clanging Cymbal," (Box-folder 3: 25)
  - 1964 September. "That Day Alone," opening vespers (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - 1964 November. "The Coming Revolution in Higher Education," Rockford Rotary, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - 1965 June. "To Be Or Not To Be," commencement address, New Berlin, Wisconsin High School (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - 1965 September. "The Relativity of Relativity,", 1965-1966 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - 1965 October. "The Mark of Academic Honor," Carthage College (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - 1966 January. "Academia--Community or Computer?" Monmouth College, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - 1966 May. "Planned Mediocracy in Higher Education," Kiwanis Club, Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - 1966 July. "To Teach or to Learn--That Is the Question," Institute on Education, Madison College (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - 1966 September. "Freedom's Discipline," (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - 1963 June. "Sounding Brass or a Clanging Cymbal," (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - 1963 September. "Quality in Higher Education,", 1962-1963 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - 1964 February. "The Beloit Plan: One College's Answer to a Dilemma in American Education," Union League Club of Chicago, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - 1964 June. "Form Follows Function," commencement address, Milwaukee University School, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - 1967 April. "If This Be Heresy..." Ripon College (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - 1967 April. "I'm For the Upperdog," (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - 1967 September. "This Holy Ground," convocation address (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - 1967 October. "One World To Conquer," Wayland Academy (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - 1968 September. "The Ghetto of the Human Mind," (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - 1967 May. "Let's Start Thinking Straight and Talking Straight About the Future of the Liberal Arts College," Central Association of College and University Business Officers (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - 1968. "What Price Prejudice!", 1964-1968 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - 1968 June. "Sounding Brass or a Clanging Cymbal," commencement address, Loyola University (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - 1970 June. "Night and Day, Day or Night," commencement address, Whitefish Bay High School (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - 1963 January. "Low-Tuition Principle for Public Higher Education," NEA Jounral, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - "What is Beloit College?", 1967-1968 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    Scope and Contents note
    Alternate title: "The Essence of Beloit College"
  - 1971. "Collegiate Resurrection?" in Campus in Change, Wisconsin Academic conference of Student Governments (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - 1976 May. "A Time for Renewal," Yankton College (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - 1977 February. "Allies--Not Enemies," Alderson-Broaddus College (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - "An Old Idea Whose Time Has Come,", circa 1978 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - 1989 June. "The Role and Importance of Christian Education," (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - 1978 May. "We The People...", Doane College Commencement (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - 1978 November. "Let's Have Substance, Not Form," Mid-American Association of Educational Opportunity Program Personel (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - 1984. "Ruminations of a Retired Academician," (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - "Mistaken Identities," commencement address, 1954-1976 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    Includes typescript of "Education for the Profession of Leadership," 1954
- Economics, Business, and Finance File
  - "Thoughts on Executive Compensation,", 1983 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - "A Speculative Inquiry Into the Future Role of Debt," Robert Swanson Agency, Union League Club, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - "A Case for Historical Accounting,", 1977-1980 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - "The New Economics," Milwaukee Sentinel Forum, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Review of Effects of Taxation: Corporate Financial Policy by Dan Throop Smith, 1952 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - "Administering Business Profits," Business Finanace Handbook, Prentice-Hall, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - "Size of Office as a Competitive Factor in Small Loan Business," Northwestern University, 1949 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - "Problems of Reconciling Economic Objectives With a Mobilization Program," Washington University, St. Louis, 1952 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - "The University and The Business Community," for Arthur Compton, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Mortgage bankers speech, 1952 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - "An Economic Appraisal of Convenience and Advantage Licensing by Small Loan Statutes,", 1950-1953 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - "The Economics of Fair Changes for Consumer Loans,", 1929-1953 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    Includes printed copy of "Volume as It Affects Operating Ratios," National Consumer Finance Association, 1953
  - "The Sociology of Consumer Credit," National Retail Credit Association, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Speech, Institute on Consumer Credit, Marquette University, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - "Expanded Cooperation Between Commercial Banks and Finance Companies in Financing Consumer Credits,", 1947 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Small loan symposium, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Harris Trust Plan article, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - "Size of Office as a Competitive Factor in the Small Loan Business,", 1951 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - "A Monetary Accounting Approach to the Matter of Savings and Investment,", circa 1949, undated (Box-folder 7: 8)
    Unpublished typescript
  - "Statement of Miller Upton Before the House Ways and Means Committee with Reference to President Kennedy's Tax Proposal,", 1963 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Blue Ribbon Tax Committee speech, Milwaukee Kiwanis Club, 1961 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Statements on philosophy of life, 1941-1990 (Box-folder 7: 11)
    Includes "My Living Philosophy," "Nature of My Belief," and "The Logical Basis of the Pacifistic Belief"
  - "Society, the Individual, and the State,", 1989-1990 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Federal Home Loan Bank, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 7: 13)
- Richard M. Nixon File
  - Kent State shootings
    - Open letter to Nixon, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - Clippings and unfavorable responses to open letter, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - Letters
      Responses to Upton's open letter to Nixon
      - A-C, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 3)
      - D-H, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 4)
      - I-L, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 5)
      - M-Q, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 6)
      - R-Z, 1970 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Telegram regarding end of Vietnam War, 1973 (Box-folder 9: 2)
    Includes photocopy of letter from Nixon to Upton
- Speeches and Writings
  - "The Public Is Not a Sector--A Comment,", undated (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - "A Year That Will Live in Infamy,", 1984-1985 (Box-folder 9: 4-5)
  - "Where Does Sovereignty Reside," League of Suburban Municipalities, 1981 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - "Not Peace But a Sword," sermon, First Presbyterian Church, 1965 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - "The Security of Quest," Chicago Sunday Evening Club, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - "A Platform for Renewal," American Association of University Women, Milwaukee Chapter, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 9: 9-10)
  - Johnson Foundation conference, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - "Freedom Fighters,", 1989 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - "The Moral Imperatives of Private Enterprise,", 1987-1988 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - "A Platform for Renewal," address, University of Tennessee-Chattanooga, 1973 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - "Hoover, Roosevelt, and the 'Mess' Reagan Has to Deal With," letter to the editor, 1981 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - "The Business Executive as Societal Leader,", 1979 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - "For Want of a Gyroscope Society Is Lost," American Association of Advertising Agencies, 1968 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - "It's Time to Start Emphasizing the Dominant Good of the United States,", 1968 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - "I'm for Red White and Blue Power," in Chicago Tribune, 1968 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - "Conservative Not Conservator,", 1967-1968 (Box-folder 10: 8-9)
  - "Private Enterprise and the Business Executive,", 1955, undated (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - "Nothing Useless Is or Low,", 1968-1970 (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - "To Lead or Not To Lead," National Federation of State High School Athletic Associations, 1970 (Box-folder 10: 12)
- Federal Union File
  - Achilles, Theodore C., 1981-1982 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Airlie House Conference, Jim Huntley study, 1981 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Background information, 1927-1976 (Box-folder 11: 3)
    Includes issues of Freedom & Union and printed matter concerning the founding of Federal Union
  - Blackwelder, Justin, 1982 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Board of Directors and board meetings, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 11: 5-7)
  - Brooks, George, 1983 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Budget and program, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - By-laws, 1940-1979 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Campaign, undated (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Center for the Study of Federalism, 1982 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - Chapman, Brewster, 1980 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - Chapman, Patricia, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - Chips, Roy B., 1981 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Comments, 1980-1983, undated (Box-folder 12: 6)
    Includes typescripts of speeches and writings by Upton, such as "Federal Union--A Practical Means to Peace," "The Task to Be Done," "As I See It," and "Human Rights and the Goal of Federal Union"
  - Congressional resolutions, 1977-1980, undated (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Constitution Day proposal, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - Con-West Oxford Conference, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 12: 9-10)
  - Council of Scholars, 1977 (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - Credo, 1974-1976, undated (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - Dennis, Don, 1978-1988 (Box-folder 12: 13)
  - Doman, Nicholas, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 12: 14)
  - Dorfman, Cynthia, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 12: 15)
  - Editorial program, 1979, undated (Box-folder 12: 16)
  - European community, 1981 (Box-folder 12: 17)
  - Europe trip, undated (Box-folder 12: 18)
    Includes typescript of trip report/travel diary
  - Executive Committee, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 12: 19)
  - Federalist Party, undated (Box-folder 12: 20)
  - The Federator, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Feldman, George J., 1977 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Financial reports, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Findley's Resolution, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Foundation approaches to Federal Union, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Frank, Herb, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Freedom & Union, 1955-1980, undated (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Fund raising, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Givens, Richard A., 1979 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Greene, Thurston, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - Haig foreign policy, 1981 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Harris, Morgan, 1981 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - Hepburn, Charles, 1977 (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - Huntley, Jim, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - International division, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Israel, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Kreeger, David Lloyd, 1978 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Lamb, F. Gilbert, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Lehleitner, George H., 1980-1981 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - McKee, Thomas Hudson, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Mathews, John, 1979 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Memphis award trip, 1979 (Box-folder 14: 9)
    Concerns the National Student Editorial Contest sponsored by Federal Union
  - Miscellaneous, 1978-1989 (Box-folder 14: 10-11)
  - "More Is Less,", 1979, undated (Box-folder 14: 12)
    Includes typescripts
  - Mulleneux, Hugh, 1980 (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - Nominating Committee, 1979, undated (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - North American delegation, 1979, undated (Box-folder 14: 15)
  - North Atlantic Assembly, 1979 (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - OCRI Foundation, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 14: 17)
  - Oram International Corp., 1975-1977 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Osborn, Stellanova, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Program materials, 1977, undated (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Reading, crucial, 1939-1976 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Reference materials, 1962-1977, undated (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Ritter, Wolfgang, 1961, 1978, undated (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Schmidt, Adolph, 1981 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Smith, Henry P., III, 1981-1989 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Standing Conference of Atlantic Organizations, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Stover, Carl, 1978 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Strauss, Simon D., 1977 (Box-folder 15: 11)
  - Streit, Clarence, 1940-1986, undated (Box-folder 15: 12-13)
  - Streit, Clarence (cont'd.), 1940-1986, undated (Box-folder 16: 1-2)
  - Strickler, Merv, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Upton, Miller, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Wagner, Rudolph, 1980 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Ware, John, III, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - World federalism, 1978, undated (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Youth Section, 1974-1978, undated (Box-folder 16: 8)
- United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) File
  - General Conference file
    - Sixteenth Session
      - General, 1970 (Box-folder 16: 9-11)
      - General (cont'd.), 1970 (Box-folder 17: 1)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 17: 2-3)
      - Position papers, 1970 (Box-folder 17: 4-5)
        Includes paper by Upton
      - Press releases, 1970 (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - Seventeenth Session
      - Correspondence and notes, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 17: 7)
      - Correspondence and notes (cont'd.), 1972-1973 (Box-folder 18: 1)
      - Reports, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - Eighteenth Session
      - Reports, 1974 (Box-folder 18: 3)
      - Speech and notes, 1974 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - Nineteenth Session, 1976 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Printed matter, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 18: 6-9)
  - Printed matter (cont'd.), 1969-1978 (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
  - Subject file
    - General, 1965-1976 (Box-folder 19: 3)